

# Suman Kanti Roy

- +91 7411940354
- ★ Kolkata, West Bengal
- https://s-kroy.github.io/ux/
- roy.sumankanti@gmail.com

## **Technical Tools**

Adobe XD	O	O	
Figma	0	0	•
Photoshop	0	0	•
Illustrator	0	0	
InDesign	0		0
After Effects	0		0
HTML & CSS	0		0
VS Code	0		0
Bootstrap		0	0
Power BI	•	0	0

"With great power...comes great responsibility"

Stan Lee

Writer | Editor | Publisher | Producer
Marvel Comics

UX & UI
10+ years
experience



## **Professional Profile**

I'm a creative professional who loves to paint on canvas and touch-screen surfaces. I do both user experience design and user interface design for interactive products, digital services & enterprise solutions. I simply try to connect the dots between human vision with machine algorithms by applying design methodology & accessibility principles. I've total 10+ years of diversified design experience across multiple domains for start-ups and leading corporate brands. I am always keen to learn new-age tech & soft skills to harness my problem-solving ability.

## **Academic Education**

#### **Bachelor of Visual Arts**

Govt. College of Art & Craft, Tripura University Drawing & Painting | 2006 - 2010

#### **Bachelor of Science**

Maharaja Bir Bikram College, Tripura University Mathematics I 2004 - 2006

# **Employment History**

17 Jan 2022 — till date

Lexmark International India Pvt. Ltd.

Usability Design Engineer

17 Mar 2017 — 15 Jan 2022 **Wipro Limited** Senior UI & UX Designer

11 Mar 2015 — 15 Mar 2017

RxPrism Health Systems Pvt. Ltd.

Creative UI & UX Designer

06 Jan 2014 — 20 Feb 2015 **Hibu India Pvt. Ltd.**Graphic & Web Designer

15 Apr 2013 — 30 Dec 2013

Bid & Hammer Fine Art Auctioneer

Visual Designer & Researcher

# **Certificate & Credentials**

- Enterprise Design Thinking Practitioner badge issued by IBM.
- Understanding Augmented Reality in Business from Skillsoft.
- Adobe XD Essentials assessment and training issued by Adobe.
- Certificate of Completion on Html-5, Css-3 & Sass from Udemy.
- Certificate of Completion on Bootstrap-4 from Udemy.

# Rewards & Recognition

- "Lexmark Chief Technology Officer Award 2022" for AR techbased retail shopping app in the Focus-2-Future, a yearly event.
- Wipro Top Gear Crowdsourcing Challenge Award for the "Digital micro prioritisation Interface" project in 2020 from Wipro Digital.
- Recognise badge credentials & 1,000 \$ rewards from Wipro on completion of training & assignment Adobe XD Essentials 2019.
- Appreciation from renowned movie Director "Atanu Ghosh" for making a logo for "Satyajit Ray Film Society Bengaluru" in 2017.
- Win the "Excellent Creative Professional Award 2015" organised by Rxprism Health System Pvt. Ltd. on World Environment Day.
- "Sumangol Sen Memorial Scholarship" for painting category from Govt. College of Arts and Craft, Agartala, Tripura in 2010.